Linlin,
临临
are you mad?
你生气啦
don't be angry, okay?
别生气了
Can't I be angry?
我能不生气吗
Look at you.
你说说你
You have a home,
跟这儿有家你不待着
but you're out here sleeping on the floor.
你出来打地铺
What do you think you're doing?
你要干什么
Do you not know
你多大岁数了
how old you are?
你自己心里不清楚吗
your situation?
你什么情况
The floor is so damp.
地上那么潮 你睡地上
If you get sick sleeping on the ground,
万一生了个病
how to tell my brother-in-law about this?
我怎么跟姐夫交代
If you're going out to work,
你要出去干活
no one's stopping you, right?
没人拦着你是吧
But you need to come home to sleep, okay?
但是你要回家住嘛
Isn't...
我那儿
Look! Look at me!
你问 你看着我
Isn't my place your home too?
我那儿是不是你家
Am I not your brother?
我是不是你弟弟
Li Lin!
李临
What?
干什么
Am I wrong?
我说得不对吗
Whether you're right or wrong,
你说得对不对
can't you just say it nicely?
你不能好好说吗
What are you doing?
你这是干吗呀
Don't look at me,
你看我干吗
look at the road!
看路
Your face was all twisted with anger.
鼻子不是鼻子
Stop being so grumpy.
脸不是脸的
Can't you speak nicely?
有话不能好好说呀
If you care about your sister,
你要是心疼姐了
just tell her,
你就告诉她
"Sister, I care about you."
说 姐 我心疼你了
Is it so hard to say something honest?
说句实话有那么难吗
Aren't we all family?
大家不是一家人吗
Always like this.
什么都是
Nothing.
没事
You're just spoiling him.
你就是给他惯的
Watch how I'll deal with him
你看我晚上回去
when we get home tonight.
怎么收拾他
Wanwan,
婉婉
Have you finished your homework?
作业都写完了
Yes,
写完了
but Zhenzhen still has a little left.
真真还差一点
Do you need to sign it?
要不要签字啊
Yes.
要
Okay. I'll sign it in a bit.
行 一会儿妈妈给你签
That's a good idea!
你这想法好啊
I'm clever, right?
我棒吧
This was Mom's idea.
这还是妈妈想出来的
So, it's like
那这样就相当于
a scarecrow
是一个稻草人
standing on the balcony. ﻿
站在阳台上
It can scare away bad guys, right?
可以吓唬坏人 是不是
That's exactly what Mom said.
妈妈也是这么说的
Mom said that too?
妈妈也这么说啊
See,
那你看
your mom and dad are totally in sync,
这爸爸跟妈妈之间
aren't we?
是不是很默契啊
What are you talking about?﻿
你们在说什么呢
Mom,
妈妈
I want dad
我想让爸爸
to bring us two sets of his clothes.
送他两件衣服
Alright, it's settled then.
那就这么定了啊
I'll take the clothes over right now.
我现在就送衣服过去
But, Wan Zhen, don't worry.
不是 婉真 你放心啊
Today
今天呢
isn't the designated visiting time,
不是这个探视时间
right?
对吧
I'll just
我呀
drop the clothes off in the basement
直接到地库把衣服给你
and leave right away.
我转身就走
I'm heading over now.
我这就过来啊
Goodbye, Dad!
爸爸再见
Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
You two told Dad
你俩跟爸爸说
that Mom was buying men's clothes?
妈妈要买男士衣服了
Yeah.
对啊
Dad has
这样子
a lot of clothes,
爸爸有很多衣服的
so, there's no need to spend money.
就不用花钱了
It's quite economical.
很省钱的
Exactly.
说得对
Zhenzhen,
真真
you didn't finish your homework,
你作业写完了吗
and you called Dad?
就开始跟爸爸打电话
Don't forget the teacher needs to sign it.
老师可要签字的
No rush.
不着急
I'll have some fruit first.
我先吃点水果
Alright.
好吧
Is it good?
好吃吗
Finish it up and get to work.
吃完赶紧写啊
Just grab a couple of clothes
拿两件你平时
you don't usually wear.
不穿的就行
This suit is easily damaged
这长期晒外面
by being left outside in the sun.
怕晒坏了
Ruined? We just buy another, right?
晒坏了咱再买 对吧
We just want people to see
咱就是给人看看
that there's a strong,
这家里边有一个有实力
reliable man in the house,
靠得住的男人
so, no one dares to mess with you.
这么着没人敢欺负你
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Has something happened
这 这家里是
at home recently?
最近出什么事了
Why the sudden urge to hang up clothes?
怎么想起挂衣服来了
No, it's just for precaution.
没有啊 以防万一
Right,
对对对
you've thought ahead.
你想得这周到啊
It's always good to be prepared.
未雨绸缪嘛
If there's nothing else, I'll leave now.
那没事我就先走了
Wait,
不是
aside from thinking about the clothes,
你除了觉得缺衣服之外
don't you think the house
你不觉得这家里边
is also missing someone?
还缺个人吗
Someone to help out.
缺一个给你搭把手的人
The property guys are more helpful.
你能干的物业都能干
That's not quite right.
这话不能这么说吧
You think the property management
我能干的
can do everything what I can?
物业他都能干吗
Well, can you borrow a work uniform
那你说 借衣服这事
from the property management
你能跟物业
and hang it up there?
借一工作服挂那儿吗
You take it back, and I'll go buy one.
你拿回去我去买
No, no.
不不 别别别 别
No need to buy one, I'll shut up.
你买什么 我不说了
I'm leaving.
我走
Come back.
你回来
Just to confirm,
跟你确认一下
can you pick up the kids
下周末接孩子的时间
an hour earlier next weekend?
能不能提前一个小时
I've been quite busy.
我最近挺忙
The sales peak season, right?
销售旺季 对吧
I understand.
能理解
I do the same when I'm busy.
我忙的时候也这样
Alright,
那这么着
I'll arrive an hour and a half earlier,
我提前一个半小时
at 7:30.
我七点半到
Eight o'clock is fine.
八点就行
Okay,
行
see you
那
at eight.
八点钟见
Ms. Chen, what a coincidence.
陈小姐 这么巧
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Mr. Yu, what a coincidence.
于先生 这么巧
I won't disturb you.
我不打扰你们了
I'm going to the gym.
我去健身房
I think you're
我觉得你啊
missing not just
你缺的不只是
reliable clothes
这靠谱的衣服
but also
还缺一个
a reliable man like me.
像我这样靠谱的男人
Having the clothes
衣服在
is like having me around.
约等于我在
You go up first.
你先上去吧
You go.
你走吧
You go first.
你先走
Your car is blocking someone.
你这车挡着人家了
Come.
来
Let's hang up
咱们把爸爸的衣服
dad's clothes, okay?
挂上好不好
Okay.
好
Dad said that
爸爸说了
hanging his clothes
挂他的衣服
is like
就好像
having him around,
他在我们身边
protecting us.
保护着咱们
Yes,
是啊
this way,
这样的话
we'll
以后
feel secure in the future.
我们就有安全感了
Aren't you going to sleep?
不睡觉吗
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Big sis's wontons are in the fridge.
冰箱里有大姐包的馄饨
I'll cook them now.
我现在去煮
Hungry?
饿了
Meng'an is hungry.
梦安饿了
I made a bowl for you too.
我也给你煮了一碗
How is it? Is it enough?
怎么样 够不够
Should I make another bowl for you?
要不再给你煮一碗
No, no, no,
不不不 不了
that's enough.
不了 不了 不了
Eating
这大晚上的
such a big bowl at this hour
吃了这么一大碗
is already too much.
已经很罪过了
You're eating for one
你现在是一个人吃
but making up for two,
两个人补
so, don't diet, okay?
千万别减肥啊
We'll diet after the baby is born.
等生完了咱再减
Don't worry,
你放心
I have a family recipe.
姐有祖传秘方
Okay,
好
I trust you.
我信姐
I was originally thinking
我原本还想着
that if you left,
你要是回去了
I would find another reason
我就再找个理由
to bring you back.
把你给拽回来
But to my surprise,
结果没承想
you never left...
你根本就没走
Look at you.
你看你
I understand you're specializing in
我知道你去学月嫂
post-natal care for me.
是为了我
Thank you, sister.
谢谢你啊 姐
Look at you,
你看你
thank you, thank you, thank you.
左一个谢 右一个谢
Aren't we family?
咱不是一家人吗
Besides,
再说
I was just idle
姐就是闲得没事干
and decided to learn to post-natal care.
去 学个月嫂
It's not just for you.
不光是为了你
I also want to make some money.
姐还想发财呢
Okay,
好
I won't delay your business.
我不耽误你发财
Yes.
对
Don't take it yet, sis.
先不收 姐
I have something to tell you.
我有几句话想跟你说
Do you
你说
remember when Li Lin and I
你还记得我跟李临
were buying this house,
要买这套房的时候
we were short of some money.
差了些钱
It was you who helped us.
还是你给添的吗
That wasn't me,
那可不是我添的啊
that was dad.
那是爸
The money he left for your wedding.
留给你们结婚的钱
Don't lie to me.
你别骗我了
Even though I never met dad,
我虽然没见过爸
I still know.
我也是知道的
Dad was sick for so long,
爸病了那么久
so, there couldn't be any money left.
哪儿还有什么钱呀
That money was all borrowed.
那都是你借来的
That was that year
那是那年
when Li Lin and I
我跟李临
went home for the holidays.
回家过节的时候
Someone came
然后有人
to collect a debt from my brother-in-law.
上门找姐夫要账
That's how we found out.
我们就知道了
Later, my brother-in-law said
后来姐夫才说
you all paid it back over several years.
你们也是还了好几年的
Look at Mr. Ouyang,
你看这个老欧阳
chattering like
怎么跟个老太太似的
an old woman,
嚼舌头啊
saying everything out loud.
什么话都往外说
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
when dad passed away,
爸走的时候
he left the clinic to him.
把诊所留给他了
So, when my brother's buying an apartment,
那我弟弟买房子
it's only right for me
姐拿点钱
to take some money.
那不是应该的吗
Yes,
应该
you are right.
你说得都对
Later, I told Li Lin
后来我就跟李临说
to give the money back to you.
把钱还给你
He said you definitely wouldn't accept it,
李临说你肯定不会要
so, I said that this apartment
我就说
should be considered as a share for you.
那这房子也得算姐一份
So,
所以
this is your home,
这就是你的家
and you can
你可以理直气壮地
live here confidently.
住在这儿
Next time if you get angry again,
下回要是再生气了
just kick him out,
你就把他撵走
but you can't leave again.
但是你不能再走了
If you leave,
你要再走的话
I'll be really upset,
我可就翻脸了啊
you know?
知道不
Well,
那
I leave these bowls here.
那我就不管了啊
Hurry up
你快快快
and rest.
快休息 休息
Once you're done,
收拾好了
go to bed quickly.
你也赶快睡觉
Is that okay?
我这么说行吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Li Lin,
李临
breakfast is ready.
吃饭喽
Auntie,
大姑
I love fried dumplings the most,
我最爱吃煎饺了
especially with meat filling.
肉馅的
I need to eat more meat,
我得多吃点肉
or else
不然我上课
my brain doesn't work well in class.
脑子都转不动了
Alright, alright, here,
好好好 来
have another one.
姑再给你一个
Eat a bit more.
多吃一点啊
Whether your brain works or not
脑子转不转的
is not related to the meat.
跟肉没什么关系
It's just that you love eating it.
就是爱吃
Your aunt,
大姑啊
it's not that I can't cook meat dishes.
不是不会做荤菜
I just think
我就是觉得吧
eating too much at night
晚上吃得太多
is not healthy,
不健康
you know?
知道吧
In the future,
以后呢
let's make our breakfasts
咱们早晨呢
more substantial,
就做得丰盛一点
right?
对吧
Traditional Chinese medicine says that
你看人家老中医说了
breakfast should
早上是吃得
be like a king's feast,
要像皇帝一样
lunch should
中午啊
be more modest,
要吃得平民一些
and dinner should be like a beggar's meal.
晚上 要吃得像乞丐
Got it?
懂不啦
So now we're
那我们现在
all like queens.
就都是娘娘啊
Come on!
来来来
Meng'an,
梦安 快来
come try this beef.
你尝尝这个牛肉
I just braised last night.
我昨天晚上新卤的
Okay.
好
What a sumptuous breakfast!
这么丰盛的早餐啊
It seems like that our sister
看来姐
has learned a lot
为了我们家的早餐啊
from Lanxiang
那是跟兰香姐
for our family's breakfasts.
学了不少啊
What?
什么
I learned from Lanxiang?
我跟兰香学的
Are you serious?
你有没有搞错啊
Those recipes from Lanxiang
兰香那几招
were actually taught by me.
还是我教的呢
Are you kidding?
你开玩笑吧你
You...
你
Oh.
对呀
Oh right, I forgot.
对 我都忘了
Lanxiang's cooking
这个
used to be
兰香姐以前做菜
so rough,
多粗糙啊
right?
是不是
Yes.
对呀
I remember,
我记得那个小炒啊
you taught her how to
什么煎饺
make the stir-fry and dumplings.
都是你教她的嘛
Yes!
对呀
So how can you say
那你怎么能说
I learned from her?
我跟她学的呢
I forgot!
我忘了嘛
Auntie,
大姑
I wanna eat fermented glutinous rice buns.
我想吃酒酿馒头
Can you make them?
你会做吗
Yes, I can.
会啊
Just wait,
你等着
You'll have them
明天早上
tomorrow morning.
姑就让你吃上
Yeah!
好
Haowen.
浩文
Here, try this.
来 你尝一尝这个
Really?
是吗
Okay, I'll go.
行行行 我去 我去
Just take care of Xin.
你照顾好心心就行了
You don't need to worry about it.
不用管了
What's wrong? Is there something?
怎么了 有事
Xiongxiong has a fever
熊熊发烧了
and might need to go to the hospital.
说可能要去医院
Haowen is afraid that his grandma
浩文怕他奶奶
won't be able to handle it alone,
一个人弄不了
so, he asked me to go and take a look.
让我过去看看
Isn't he taking care of Xin?
他不是照顾心心呢吗
I'll go with you.
我跟你一块儿
Okay.
好
No, neither of you can go.
不行 你们俩都不能去
I just took a leave.
我 我刚才请假了
I wasn't planning to
本来不是要去
go to the prenatal class anyway.
什么孕妇课堂
I figured it's okay not to go.
我觉得不去也行吧
It's not just that.
不是那么回事
You're pregnant now.
你现在是个孕妇
If Xiongxiong
熊熊发烧了
has the flu,
万一是流感
what if you catch it too?
把你传染了怎么办呀
Then I'll go by myself.
那还是我去
No, you can't go either.
不行 你也不能去
You and Meng'an
你跟梦安
are together all the time.
吃在一起睡在一起
If you get infected,
你传染了
it's like infecting her too.
不就等于给她传染了吗
Let me go.
还是我去吧
I'm familiar with the hospital.
医院我也轻车熟路啊
Even if,
万一
I'm saying even if,
我是说万一啊
it's the flu,
要真的是流感
it's okay.
也没关系啊
I'll stay at Xin's home for a couple days,
我在心心那儿住两天
and self-isolate.
自我隔离一下
It'll be fine.
不就行了吗
That's fine then.
也 也行
It's a lot of trouble for you.
那 那就辛苦您
Okay,
好
let's do it this way.
那咱们就这样啊
After breakfast,
吃完饭以后呢
you take Meng'an to her class.
你送梦安去那个上课
You can take He Lu's car to school,
你坐何璐家车 去上学
and I'll take a Uber
我呢 打个车
to take Xiongxiong to the hospital.
去带熊熊去看病
We'll split up
咱们兵分几路
and handle our own tasks.
各忙各的
The arrangements are perfect.
安排得太好了
Yes.
对
If you hadn't arranged it this way,
要不像您这么安排的话
we'd probably be a mess.
估计我们就乱套了
Leave the household matters
家里这些事啊
to me,
交给我
you can just rest assured.
你们就放心吧
Hurry up, hurry up.
来来来 快快快
Reassured!
放心
After we finish eating, let's act quickly.
吃完了咱们赶快行动
Come on,
来来来 快
Hurry up.
来
Okay, okay,
好好好
thank you, sis.
谢谢姐
Eat some meat.
你吃肉
Eat more beef.
你多吃点牛肉
Sure.
我多吃
It's high-quality protein,
这是优质蛋白
you know?
知道吗
Here, sweetheart, have some too.
来 宝贝 你也吃一点
Come on.
来
Eat up.
快吃啊
Thank you, auntie.
谢谢大姑
Come on.
对 来
Hello.
你好 大姨
Why are you coming here?
你咋来了呀
I'm to pick up the child for the doctor.
我来接孩子看病
Thanks.
谢谢
Xiongxiong will come out soon.
熊熊一会儿就出来
By the way,
那个
the driver is stuck in traffic
司机被堵在路上了
and it'll take another 20 mins or so.
还得二十多分钟呢
Is there a car at home?
家里车在吗
There is a car,
车倒是有啊
but who will drive?
谁开呀
I will.
我开
Xiongxiong, don't be afraid.
熊熊 别怕啊
Listen to the doctor at the hospital.
到医院要听医生的话
You'll get better soon.
很快就好了
Yes.
是
Li Jing,
李静啊
I heard you used to be
听说 你以前
a head nurse, right?
是护士长 是吧
Yes, I was a head nurse.
对 我是护士长
Um...
大姨
is he still feverish?
他现在还烧吗
When he
刚才那个
came out just now,
出来的时候
his temperature was
给他量了一下
thirty-eight point six degrees.
三十八度六
That's pretty high.
那还挺高的
Yes.
是啊
Does his stomach hurt?
他肚子难受吗
He's been vomiting and having diarrhea.
就是上吐下泻的呀
What did you give him to eat?
那您给他吃什么了
Grandma bought me ice cream.
奶奶给我买了冰淇淋
Aren't you
还不是你啊
crying and shouting for ice cream.
哭着喊着非要吃冰淇淋
This child just won't listen.
这孩子就是不听话
Alright, I understand now.
行了 我知道了
It might be a stomach flu.
可能是胃肠感冒
It's okay,
没关系啊
at the hospital,
到医院
maybe a drip will do the trick.
可能打个点滴就好了
That's good.
那就好
Li Jing,
李静
I really want to thank you
今天的事
for today.
真的要感谢你啊
We truly owe you a lot.
真的多亏你呀
I'm glad to help.
大姨 您看您说的
We're family, right?
咱不是一家人吗 对吧
Yes, exactly.
对 对
I know.
大姨 我知道
You're taking care of the kids,
您来给儿子带孩子啊
and it's a big responsibility.
责任重大
Yes.
对
We shouldn't add trouble to them,
咱不能给人添麻烦
right?
对吧
Absolutely right.
太对了
It's really hard to
现在这么大的孩子
handle a child this age.
特别不好带
You need to set rules for him.
您得给他立规矩
You can't let him
不能由着他
do whatever he wants.
想干吗就干吗
Right, right.
对对对
Did you hear that?
听见没
No more cold drinks in the future.
以后不能吃这么多冷饮
Yes.
听见了
Good boy.
听话啊
This child is pitiful.
这孩子可怜
Lanxiang,
兰香啊
don't give her
你就别给她
any more pork trotter soup.
炖什么猪蹄子汤了
Keep the diet lighter, okay?
清淡一点好吗
I'll call
我马上给
Mr. Ouyang right away
老欧阳打个电话
and ask him to change the recipe.
让他换个方子
I guarantee it'll be fine.
保证没问题
Okay.
行
Once he sends the recipe,
他把方子发过来
I'll send it to you via WeChat.
我就微信发给你啊
Alright, that's settled.
好 就这样啊
You're coming.
来了
How is it?
怎么样
Last night,
昨天晚上
he didn't sleep well at all.
一宿都没好好睡
It's okay.
没事
Let him sleep a bit longer.
让他多睡会儿
We're not
反正咱们俩又没事
in a hurry.
多等会儿呗
By the way,
对了
let me tell you
来 我正好跟你说一下
about this medicine.
这个药
Look,
你看
this one is for reducing fever.
这个药啊 是退烧的
It should only be taken
不到三十八度五
if the fever reaches 38.5°C or higher.
是不能吃的
Okay?
好吧
If it does,
如果 烧到三十八度五
give him one packet.
吃一包
Okay.
好的
This one is for digestion,
这个是消化的
he should take it
一天三次
three times a day before meals.
饭前吃
Okay.
好
Okay?
好吧
Okay, okay.
好的 好的
Besides medicine and injections,
咱们啊 不光吃药打针
you also need to watch your diet.
这个饮食上也得注意
Make sure the diet stays light,
一定吃得清淡点
especially with the changing season.
现在是换季
Many kids have gastrointestinal illnesses.
肠胃感冒的孩子特别多
You must pay attention.
必须注意
Okay, okay.
是的 是的
Li Jing.
李静
Thanks again for coming today.
今天真的感谢你啊
I really didn't know what to do
你要是不来
if you hadn't come.
我都不知道怎么办好
I'm always confused
我这人哪
when I get to the hospital.
一到医院我就发蒙
And the nanny at home
你说家里那个小保姆
isn't reliable.
也指望不上
Thank you, really.
真的谢谢你
It's nothing.
这么点小事 算什么呢
We're family,
咱不是一家人吗
right?
对吧
Yes, yes.
是是是
It's my pleasure to help you.
为你服务 我高兴
Please don't be so formal with me.
千万不要跟我客气啊
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
I'll take a look.
我看看
That child is crying a lot,
这小孩哭得特别厉害
probably due to digestive issues.
肯定是肠胃不好
I'll go check on him.
我去看看啊
Sister,
姐
I know.
我知道
Recently, everyone's been out of sorts.
最近大伙也都没心情
Okay, okay.
好 好好好
We'll have another one
等回过头
in a few days.
咱们找日子再补一个
Okay, sister.
好的 姐
You go ahead and handle things.
那您先忙
Okay, okay.
好好好
Honey,
老婆
they are too busy,
姐他们也忙
so, I told her not to come.
我就让她别来了
It was already a rescheduled event,
本来也是补过
and you insisted on choosing a weekday.
你非挑个工作日
Sister and brother-in-law are so busy,
姐和姐夫多忙呀
who has time to come?
谁有工夫过来啊
Honey, it's really my fault.
老婆 这真的怪我
I was only thinking about picking a date.
我光想着挑日子了
I've been so mixed up
这产假休的
with this maternity leave.
我都把自己给休糊涂了
It's all for me?
都是为了我呗
Accompanying me on maternity leave
陪着我休产假
delayed your important matter.
耽误你大事了
Honey, don't say that.
老婆 这怎么能这么说
I wouldn't dare.
那我哪儿敢哪
How about this,
这样
when our little baby
等咱们家小西瓜
turns 100 days old,
百天的时候
we'll make it up with a big celebration,
咱补一个大的
book a big hotel,
包一个大的酒店
a five-star one,
五星级的
and hold a big celebration party
咱做一个大场子
with a sense of ceremony.
有仪式感
Is that okay?
好吧
How's Xiongxiong doing?
熊熊怎么样了
It's just gastroenteritis,
就是肠胃炎
and the fever is almost gone.
发烧呢 也快好了
How did he get gastroenteritis?
怎么会肠胃炎呢
What did mom give him to eat?
妈给他吃什么了
The issue is that he's staying at
关键是姥姥奶奶家
his grandma's and granny's alternately.
他轮着住
and no one keeps an eye on him.
也没人管他
It's unclear how it happened.
搞不清楚到底怎么
Are you blaming my mom?
你往外择自己妈是吧
You mean my mom gave him the wrong thing?
就是我妈给他吃错了呗
Honey,
媳妇
I really didn't mean it that way.
我 我真的不是这意思
I...
我
The teachers told me that
他们老师跟我说了
several of his classmates
现在他们同学
have gastroenteritis too.
好几个都得肠胃炎了
It's a seasonal issue.
季节问题
Enough of this,
行了 别吵了
I'm going to sleep.
我睡了
Okay,
好好好
okay,
来来来
let's cover the quilt tightly.
把被子盖好
Honey,
我媳
I want to say,
我跟你说啊
I'm really happy
我现在就愿意
about just the two of us.
咱俩二人世界
They are not coming
他们没有来
is just what I wanted.
正中我的下怀
It's perfect.
太好了
This is our time.
这是咱俩的时刻
Aren't you planning
你不是要给你的
a party for your little sweetheart?
小情人办派对吗
Honey,
老婆
The nanny takes care of Little Watermelon.
小西瓜还有月嫂呢
You're still the most important, honey.
最重要的还是我的宝贝
In my heart, it's only you, not her.
我的心里只有你没有她
You need to believe that my feelings
你要相信我的心意
are genuine.
并不假
Honey,
老婆
you are the most, most, most,
你是我心里最最最
most amazing woman in my heart.
最伟大的女性
Come on.
来了
I miss Xiongxiong.
我想熊熊了
It's okay,
没事
once Xiongxiong gets better,
等熊熊病好了
I'll bring him over and sleep together,
咱把他接来
the three of us.
咱们仨睡一起
Come on.
来啦
It's okay.
没事 来
Who's here, so disappointment?
谁呀 这么扫兴
I'm coming.
来了
Xu Mengxin's daughter.
许梦心之女
The result of the hearing screening
听力筛查
is out.
复查结果出来了
She still failed the left ear test.
左耳还是不通过
What should we do?
那怎么办啊
Wait
等
until the hundred-day mark
百天的时候
and go to a big hospital for a follow-up.
到大医院复诊吧
Okay, okay.
好吧 好吧
Here's the report.
这是报告单
What should we do?
怎么办呀
Little Watermelon is a girl.
小西瓜是个女孩子
If she has hearing problems
她要是因为听力有问题
and needs to wear a hearing aid,
她戴个助听器
it will be so ugly.
她丑死了
Honey,
老婆
don't worry.
你也别着急
The doctor said
医生说现在
there are multiple possibilities
检查过程中
in the current testing process.
有多种可能
He said it's possible
他说有可能
that the ear canal
孩子刚生下来
might be blocked with
新生儿她那个
earwax since the baby was just born.
耳屎堵了耳道了
Also, last time she
再说她上次查的时候
couldn't hear in both ears,
不是俩耳朵都不通
but now one ear is fine.
现在还通了一个呢
Isn't that a good thing?
这不好事吗
No,
不好
not at all.
一点都不好
Honey,
老婆
don't be upset.
别难过啊
Here,
来
honey,
老婆
look at this little cake,
你看这小蛋糕
isn't it nice?
多好啊
It even has flowers.
还有花呢
Sweets will cheer you up.
吃甜的心情好
Have a bite, open your mouth.
来一口 张嘴
I'm not in the mood to eat.
吃不下
Have a bite.
来一口
I'm coming.
来了啊
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
It's you.
您二位来了
Look at her little mouth.
你看 你看她小嘴
Uncle, Auntie,
叔叔 阿姨
I'll first take the baby for a bath.
我先带宝宝去洗个澡
Okay, okay.
好好好
This little girl.
这个小东西
Be gentle.
轻点啊
Haowen,
浩文
aren't you going to accompany your baby?
你不跟着去看着孩子啊
Or you take me
不 你带我去那个
to the bath area.
洗澡的地方
I need to keep an eye on the baby.
我得去看着孩子
The baby's ears
这孩子耳朵里
can't get wet.
她不能进水
It's fine, mom.
没事 妈 妈
Just stay here
您在这儿 陪着
and chat with Xin.
心心再聊会儿天
Dad hasn't seen Xin for a month, yet.
爸一个月都没见心了
I'll go.
我去
You go?
你去啊
I'll go, I'll go.
我去 我去
Trust me.
您放心
Okay, keep an eye on her.
行 那你看着点啊
Okay.
好嘞
Dad,
爸
don't stand there, sit down.
别站着 来 坐
Slow down, slow down.
慢点 慢点
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's not your fault.
不怪你
It's my fault.
就怪我
I made you so angry like this.
我把你气成这个样子
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay,
挺好
I'm happy.
高兴
I'm sorry, dad.
对不起 爸爸
I'm sorry.
对不起
Xin,
心心
come here, don't cry.
来 别哭啊
Look,
你看
how is your dad doing?
你爸怎么样
He seems to be recovering well.
恢复还挺好的吧
Thanks for all your hard work, Mom.
辛苦你了 妈
Don't cry, don't cry.
不哭 不哭 不哭
Do you want to try Mom's wontons?
你想不想吃妈包的馄饨
I'll bring them to you tonight.
妈晚上给你送来
No need, there's everything here.
不用了 这儿什么都有
No need.
不需要
Eating hospital food all the time,
老吃医院的饭
isn't that boring?
那不腻吗
Just take care of dad.
照顾我爸就好
I don't need anything.
我什么都不用
It's fine.
没事
Lanxiang is at home.
家里有兰香呢
She's young and capable,
她年轻能干
and she's your brother-in-law's relative.
又是你姐夫的实在亲戚
Your mom is enjoying
你妈我现在
some peace now.
可享清福了
Really?
真的吗
I heard that my dad's
我听说我爸
rehabilitation is quite troublesome.
现在做康复挺麻烦的
It's not troublesome.
我不麻烦
You know, your dad exercises
你看你爸每天
at home every day.
在家锻炼身体
The doctors at the community hospital
那社区医院的医生
come to our home for rehabilitation.
都上门康复
I'm just supervising
我就在边上
on one side.
监工
Cooking and cleaning
那个做饭哪 打扫啊
are all done by Lanxiang.
都是兰香干
We estimate,
我跟你说啊
by the time you
等你从月子中心
leave the postpartum care center,
出去的时候
your dad might even
那你爸可能都能
be able to push the stroller
帮你推着婴儿车
around the street.
满街溜达了
Strolling with the baby.
遛娃
Okay, okay.
你遛弯儿 遛弯儿
I'll exercise.
我锻炼身体
Let me tell you,
我跟你说呀
I accompany
我每天啊
your dad every day
没事我就陪着你爸
for a walk.
走一走 走一走
The doctor says that
人家大夫都说了
walking is good.
就得多走 没坏处
Your dad used to
你爸原来老在那个
sit at the senior center,
老年中心
playing cards and chess,
坐那儿打牌 下棋
not moving around,
也不动换
which easily leads to blood vessel clogs.
那血管可不是容易堵吗
From now on, I'll supervise
我今后啊 就监督好他
his exercise,
锻炼身体
and he's not allowed to eat braised pork
不许吃红烧肉
or drink alcohol.
不许喝酒
It's okay, it's okay.
好了 好了
Don't cry.
不哭
What is this?
这是什么呀
It's a bracelet,
镯子啊
you wore it when you were little.
你小时候戴过
I wore it when I was little?
我小时候戴过
Really?
戴过吗
You wore it when you were born.
刚出生的时候戴过
This.
这个
It was when you were about this big.
就 就那么大点的时候
I wore it when I was little.
小的时候戴过
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
When you were just born,
你刚出生那会儿啊
just like
跟你这个小西瓜
this Little Watermelon now,
可像了
you were also premature.
也是早产
But you were born
不过你那时候
in winter,
是冬天生的
it was cold,
天冷
and you swallowed some amniotic fluid,
出生的时候呛了口羊水
which made you cough and have a fever.
这老咳嗽 老发烧还
You're such a little one,
那那么点小孩
to take much medicine.
没法吃太多的药啊
Your dad
那你爸
is from the North,
他不是北方人吗
and they believe that
他们那边就讲究
if you wrap a red string
说这个
around the bracelet
镯子上缠根红绳
and put it on the baby's foot,
然后套在那个脚上
it helps
这孩子啊
prevent illness.
就不容易生病
You know what,
你别说啊
it actually worked.
还挺神的
Not sure if you had
也不知道是不是
reached 100 days by then,
过了百天啊
but
反正
once you put that on,
你戴上这个之后啊
no coughing and the fever cleared up.
不咳了 也不烧了
Right, Xu?
是吧 老许
Useful.
好使
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
later,
待会儿啊
you put this on Little Watermelon too.
你给小西瓜也戴上
Next time around,
没准下一次
maybe her left ear will work just fine.
那小西瓜耳朵就能通啦
Thank you, dad.
谢谢爸
Great, then no sickness and no trouble,
这样啊 就没病没灾的
warding off all illnesses.
消除百病
Thank you, mom.
谢谢妈
Congratulations,
恭喜你啊
you've reached three months,
满三个月了
you can set up your medical records now.
可以建档了
At your age,
你这个岁数
you're considered a high-risk pregnancy.
高危产妇
I don't feel anything,
我没什么感觉
why is it high-risk?
怎么就高危了呢
Age makes your pregnancy high-risk.
到了年龄就是高危
You've had to get pregnancy support twice.
你这保胎都保两回了
Isn't that high-risk?
还不高危
Be careful.
注意点吧
Age doesn't spare anyone.
年纪不饶人
My health is fine.
我身体还行
I conceived naturally.
我是自然怀孕的
Yes, yes,
对对对
you're the pregnant one,
你是孕妇
you're always right.
你说得都对
Look,
你看看
your blood lipids and blood pressure.
你这个血脂 血压
Age slows down your metabolism.
年龄大了 代谢变慢了
so, you have to control your diet.
一定要控制饮食
You should attend the prenatal class.
去上孕妇课堂吧
It's about dietary nutrition today.
今天是膳食营养
Make sure to learn well.
好好学习学习
Can I not go?
可 可以不去吗
No,
不行
if you don't attend the prenatal training,
不上孕妇培训
we won't set up medical records for you.
不给建档啊
Just go and learn,
去学学吧
it won't hurt.
没坏处
Take this.
拿着
Now, regarding pregnancy nutrition,
那么孕期的营养呢
let's compare it
我们用一个最简单的
with a simple dietary pyramid.
膳食宝塔来比较
During pregnancy,
那么孕期呢
as for cooking oil,
我们看食用油
usually,
一般的一天就是
25 g oil and 6 g salt for the whole day.
二十五克油 六克盐
How much is
那么二十五克油
25 grams of oil?
是多少呢
Let's take a look
我们就看一下
at our model.
我们的模型
This amount of oil is 25 grams.
这个油就是二十五克
During pregnancy,
我们孕期呢
the intake of oil and salt is controlled,
就是每天二十五克
just 25 grams a day.
要控油控盐啊
Oil
那么
has a high-calorie content,
油的热量是相当高的
and this is the amount of oil for one day.
这是我们一天的油量
As for salt,
那么一天的盐呢
it's 6 grams per day.
是六克盐
Do you know
大家知道
how much 6 grams of salt is?
六克盐是多少吗
Let me introduce everyone
给大家介绍一下啊
to our new
这位是我们新来的
Deputy Director of Content Center,
内容中心的副总监
Huang Sisi.
黄思思
Hello everyone,
大家好
I'm happy to join Xinmiao,
很高兴来到新苗
and I'm excited to work together.
很期待与大家共事
Please take care of me.
多关照
Where's Meng'an?
梦安呢
Not on leave for pregnancy again?
不会又请假安胎去了吧
How could that be?
怎么会呢
Director Xu will be here soon.
许总监马上就到
Rachel,
瑞秋啊
please show Sisi around
你带着思思
around the office.
熟悉一下工作环境
Okay.
好
Hello.
你好
I'm Ling Meichuan.
我是凌美川
I've heard of you for a long time,
早就听说过您
a Top 10 Tech Woman.
互联网十大杰出女性
You're truly remarkable,
非常非常优秀
and I want to learn from you.
我要向您学习
Deputy Director Ling.
凌副总监
Yes, yes.
对对对
Hello, hello.
您好 您好
I've seen you before, haven't I?
我说怎么这么眼熟呢
You're the one
就是跟我们
who participated
许总监参加的
in the same event as Director Xu, right?
是同一个活动 是吧
Yes.
对
Yes,
对啊
a Top 10 Tech Woman,
互联网十大杰出女性
just like Director Xu.
跟许总监一样
You're too kind, too kind.
过奖 过奖
Hello,
喂
I'm at the mall.
我在商场呢
Why aren't
你们的监督员
your supervisors here?
怎么不在呢
How can I ensure
那我怎么保证
the accuracy of the data?
数据的准确性呢
Have them come back immediately.
让他们赶紧回来吧
Are you from the client company?
您是甲方公司的人吗
Yes, that's right.
对啊
The strict boss lady
就是群里说的那个
they're talking about in the group.
严格女魔头
Exactly,
没错
that's me.
正是我
I need data from 9 a.m.
我要的是早上九点
to 9 p.m.,
到晚上九点的数据
but you were off-duty
可是你们离岗了
for such a long time.
这么长时间
We were only gone for a short while.
我们就出去了一小会儿
Besides,
再说了
today is a workday
今天是工作日
and there are fewer commercial demands.
商业需求人少
This kind of mother and baby product
这种母婴产品
targets
针对的人群
full-time moms,
是全职宝妈
so, it doesn't matter whether
它不存在于什么
it's a workday or a weekend.
工作日还是休息日
You were off-duty for over an hour.
你们离岗了一个多小时
How can you provide me
怎么样才能给我
with the most accurate real-time data?
最真实的一手数据
Just head-counting, huh?
不就是数人头吗
Why make it sound so grand?
说这么高大上干吗
You're finance
你们也是学金融
or economics students, right?
学经济的学生吧
You should understand
应该知道这个
the importance of data.
数据的重要性
Only the most accurate data
只有最真实的数据
can lead to the most precise judgments.
才能做出最准确的判断
Don't you get that?
这一点你们都不懂吗
Let me put it this way, madam.
这么说吧 姐
After graduation,
我毕业之后
I didn't know what I wanted to do,
我干什么都不知道
but I definitely didn't want to do
但就是不会干你这种
this kind of counting job.
数人头的破工作
I'm quitting.
我不干了
What's wrong?
干吗
Let me go.
撒开
Let him go.
让他走
My partner has left,
那 那我搭档都走了
madam,
姐
will we continue today?
那咱们今天还继续吗
Of course, we'll continue.
当然继续啊
I'll stay with you.
我陪你
Okay,
好
have a seat.
你坐
By the way,
对了 姐
since you're from the client company,
您都是甲方的人了
why are you still out here
为什么还要出来
counting the number of people?
数人头啊
Many companies
现在很多公司呢
now prefer to
喜欢把这一些
outsource this kind of work.
交给外包公司来做
Actually,
其实
When I first started working,
我刚出道的时候呢
I would personally
也会亲自到
go to the shopping mall
商场来数人头
to count people and verify the data.
确认一遍的
It's not much different
那这不跟大学毕业
from a university graduate
去拧螺丝
working as a screw-tightener.
有什么区别啊
But if you have the ability,
但如果你有能力的话
you wouldn't be doing just that forever.
你不会一直拧螺丝啊
If you don't have the ability,
如果没有能力的话
you might not
那恐怕连螺丝
even do that well.
都拧不好了
You're right.
您说得对
Deputy Director Huang,
黄副总监
you were a director at Blue Ocean
你以前是蓝海的总监
and now you're here as a deputy director.
到这儿来当副总监
You must feel aggrieved.
真是委屈你了
Not at all.
不委屈
I get along well with Mr. Zhang
我跟张总在业务方向上
on the business front,
很谈得来
and I admire Xinmiao's philosophy.
而且我欣赏新苗的理念
In this position,
在这个岗位上
I think I can add more value.
我想能发挥更大的价值
I don't know much
业务方向的事
about the business side.
我就不大懂了
The other day,
那天我看到你们
saw your award ceremony live that day.
颁奖的直播视频了
Meichuan, you were there, right?
美川 你在吧
Yes, I was.
我在
The scene was packed with people,
现场人山人海的
and you and Mr. Yu
你和于总
were hugging so tightly
抱得那么紧
and couldn't part for a long time.
久久都不能分开
Were you trying to prove to everyone
你是想向大家证明
that you're not together?
你们俩没有关系 是吧
What do you think?
你说呢
These are small welcome gifts
二位
for you two.
小小见面礼
I can't accept this.
这我可不能要
It might be considered bribery.
这有行贿的嫌疑
You all carry on.
你们忙
Thank you.
谢谢
I especially like this brand.
我特别喜欢这个牌子
Pick a color yourself.
自己选个颜色
I heard that Mr. Zhang loves green tea.
听说了张总爱喝绿茶
This is Longjing.
龙井
Try it out.
尝尝
Okay.
好
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Drink it while it's fresh.
趁新鲜喝
What a good tea.
好茶呀
What's the situation
你跟那个蓝海的于总
with you and Mr. Yu from Blue Ocean now?
现在是什么情况
Former boss.
前任老板
We have no current relationship.
现在没有任何关系了
Of course,
当然了
he will always be the mentor
他永远是那个
who introduced me to the industry.
带我出道的恩师
That won't change.
这点不会变
We've gathered
我们呢 对你
some side information about you,
侧面地了解了一下
and not all of it
这个风评啊
is positive.
也不都是好的
So,
所以我现在是
I'm using you under pressure.
顶着压力来用你
You're a new here,
你是个空降兵
so, you should have a sense of crisis.
要有危机感才是
I understand.
都明白
Really appreciate your recognition.
特别感谢张总的赏识
I will bring all
我会把我所有的
my resources and value
资源跟价值
to Xinmiao
都带进新苗
to alleviate your pressure.
来化解张总的压力
As for those reviews,
至于那些风评
I don't care.
我不在乎
I believe
我认为那是
that represents my influence.
有影响力的体现
So, tell me,
那你说说
what can you bring to Xinmiao?
你能给新苗带来什么
Here's a welcome gift for Xinmiao.
给新苗的见面礼
What's going on?
什么情况了
Oh,
不是
why did you just get back?
你怎么才回来呀
I was held up by the doctor
被医生留在那儿
at a maternity class.
上什么孕妇课堂
If I couldn't get a stamp there,
不在那儿盖个章
they wouldn't set up a record for me.
人家不给建档
Did you get the stamp?
章盖了吗
Yes, I did.
盖了
Me, too.
我也盖了
Did it happen that quickly?
这么快吗
She came prepared.
人是有备而来的
So where is she?
那人呢
She is waiting to meet you
你办公室
in your office.
等着拜见你呢
Director Xu.
许总监
Director Huang.
黄总监
Welcome.
欢迎啊
I've been waiting for you.
我一直在等你
It's normal.
正常
Have a seat.
坐
Your office
你这个办公室
has such good lighting.
采光真好
Mr. Zhang
张总把
left the best room for you.
最好位置的房间留给你
It's clear you are
一看你就是新苗
one of Xinmiao's top talents.
最优秀的人才
You're too kind.
过奖了
It's just that over the years,
只不过是因为这些年
I've been following Mr. Zhang closely
一直跟着张总
and receiving some extra care.
特别关照罢了
That's why
所以啊
I rushed to report for duty
我赶紧来报到
and have the chance to learn from you.
有机会跟着你学习
It's my honor.
是我的荣幸
I don't dare to claim that.
不敢
Congratulations.
恭喜
This is for baby.
给宝宝的
How did you find out?
这你都知道了
Who told you that?
谁跟你说的啊
Everyone was talking about it
刚才入职的时候
when I was starting my job.
大家都在聊啊
It must have been tough for you
也是难为你了
to prepare gifts in advance.
要提前准备礼物
I won't disturb you any longer.
我不打扰你了
Balance work and rest.
劳逸结合
I will.
会的
My baby.
孩儿啊
Your mother has a tough time,
你妈不容易啊
you should be filial to me.
得孝顺她
This is a survey
这是我们春江市母婴店
of customer flow and
客流量的调查
sales of infant store of Chunjiang City.
以及门店流水的评估
Take a look.
大家可以看一下
The maternal and infant industry
这个母婴产业
is definitely
肯定是值得
worth investing in,
投的一些品类
but in niche markets,
但是呢 在细分赛道上
it still needs clear
它还是需要有明确的
user profiles and product positioning.
用户画像和产品定位
Even though they are all children,
你别看都是小孩子
a year's difference
差一岁
makes a huge impact.
就非常不一样
Yes.
是的
I believe the early childhood segment
我觉得低幼这一块呢
needs clearer positioning.
应该需要更清晰的定位
Thanks to Wendy,
多亏有温蒂姐啊
otherwise, we wouldn't
不然我们连孩子都
even have children
没有的人
to make judgments about.
很难做出判断的
So, you should hurry up and get married.
那就赶紧结婚啊
So, let Wendy
那这个项目
handle this project.
就交给温蒂负责吧
Wendy has been
温蒂为了拿到
running around
最准确的数据
to get the most accurate data,
最近一直在外面跑
which is very tough.
很辛苦啊
It's not tough.
不辛苦
There's a milk tea shop
这母婴店旁边
next to the maternal and infant store.
就是奶茶店
I drink milk tea every day
我天天喝奶茶
and have gained weight.
都喝胖了
Invoice for company reimbursement.
开发票 老板报销
Wendy,
温蒂啊
are you adapting
这段时间的工作
to the work recently?
还适应吗
It's like being in a battle every day,
每天跟打仗一样
but it's fulfilling.
但是很充实
It feels like going back to
好像回到了
when I just graduated.
刚毕业的那时候
I've been living like this
这么多年
for years.
我就这么过来的
In the future,
以后啊
each day brings more fulfillment.
你每天只会更充实
Be prepared for that.
你要有心理准备啊
Thank you.
谢谢
So,
所以啊
working so efficiently
你每天这么高效率
and diligently every day
这么勤奋地工作
is why you have achieved so much today.
才会有今天的成就
No,
不行
I need to make up
我得把之前的
for the time I lost before.
耽误的时间给抢回来
Not only will you
你不仅
make up for lost time,
会把耽误的时间抢回来
but you'll also become
你还会成为那个
the one who runs the farthest
跑得最远
and lasts the longest.
最长久的那个人
Why do you say that?
为什么这么说
Look,
你看啊
Wendy,
温蒂
when we started in the industry together,
当年我们 一起入行
it was like
就好像站在
we were on the same starting line.
同一条起跑线上
The starting gun fired,
发令枪 砰的一声响
and we all began
大家一起开始
a long-distance race.
一场长跑比赛
But the financial industry
但是金融行业啊
requires maintaining a high intensity,
要保持一个 高强度
which is really exhausting.
实在太累了
In your twenties, your body can handle it,
二十多岁身体还吃得消
but thirty-five is a threshold.
三十五岁那就是个坎
Many people
很多人呢
can't endure it.
扛不住
Their enthusiasm fades,
热情消磨掉了
and they leave or change careers.
就离开了 就转行了